(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-04T17:34:46.115750",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ラライ ラライ
La-la-lai, la-la-lai,
誰も知らない 名もない今を 駆けてゆくの
running through a nameless present known to no one,
あの三日月へ 手を伸ばして
reaching out for that crescent moon.
ラライ ラライ
La-la-lai, la-la-lai,
君を知りたい 声にならない 臆病な朝を 例え何度迎えようとも
wanting to know you, facing a cowardly morning that cannot find its voice, no matter how many times it comes.
睫毛の緒がピチンと切られたその時 世界と逸れてしまったみたいだ
The moment my eyelash thread snapped, it felt like I had drifted away from the world.
眼に写る景色が悲しく笑うなら
If the scenery reflecting in my eyes smiles sadly,
恐れずに瞼を閉じてごらん
try closing your eyelids without fear.
さあ皆さんこちらへ どうぞ鼓動の鳴る方へ
Now everyone, come here, please, to where the heartbeat echoes,
踵を打ち鳴らせ どうぞ心の踊る方へ
stamp your heels, please, to where the heart dances,
蜃気楼に飛び乗って さかさまな世界乗りこなして
leap onto a mirage and master this upside-down world.
ラライ ラライ 誰も知らない 愛を知りたいと願うおまじない
La-la-lai, la-la-lai, a spell wishing to know an unknown love,
時を超えて 宵から夜まで
transcending time, from dusk till night.
ラライ ラライ 君を知りたい 誰一人罪の笠脱ぐより
La-la-lai, la-la-lai, wanting to know you, more than anyone shedding their sins,
時は誰も待ってくれないの
time waits for no one.
残酷な運命が 逆らい得ぬ宿命が
A cruel fate, an inevitable destiny,
考える間もなく 押し寄せるなら
washing over me without a moment to think.
前が見えなくたって 君を信じてみたいの
Even if I can't see ahead, I want to try believing in you,
恐れずに一歩踏み出したら
if I take a step forward without fear.
さあ皆さんこちらへ どうぞ鼓動の鳴る方へ
Now everyone, come here, please, to where the heartbeat echoes,
踵を打ち鳴らせ どうぞ心の踊る方へ
stamp your heels, please, to where the heart dances,
さあ皆さんこちらへ どうぞ鼓動の鳴る方へ
Now everyone, come here, please, to where the heartbeat echoes,
踵を打ち鳴らせ どうぞ心の踊る方へ
stamp your heels, please, to where the heart dances,
空飛ぶ鯨に飛び乗って さかさまな世界踊り尽くせ
leap onto a flying whale and dance the upside-down world away.
ラライ ラライ
La-la-lai, la-la-lai,
誰も知らない 名もない今を 駆けてゆくの
running through a nameless, unknown present,
あの三日月へ 手を伸ばして
reaching out for that crescent moon.
ラライ ラライ 君を知りたい 声にならない 臆病な朝を
La-la-lai, la-la-lai, wanting to know you, a cowardly morning that cannot find its voice.
夢見 描い た
Even if I dream, draw it out,
願い 叶え ぬ まま
and the wish remains unfulfilled,
伸ばし た 手 届け
my outstretched hand reaches,
変ら ぬ まま
remaining unchanged.
でも 夢の中 なら ば
But if it's inside a dream,
なん だって
just what could it be?
なれる なんたって 簡単 で
You can become anything so easily.
今夜 は 鳥 ? いや 瞬く 星 ?
Tonight, is it a bird? No, a twinkling star?
夢の中 ホント に 輝く のに
Inside a dream, it really shines.
時は誰も待ってくれないの
Time won't wait for anyone.
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
With an invincible smile, it stirs up the media.
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
I want to know that secret, it's mysterious.
抜けてるところさえ彼女のエリア
Even that elusiveness is her area.
完璧で嘘つきな君は
You, who are perfect and a liar,
天才的なアイドル様
are a genius idol-sama!
今日何食べた? 好きな本は?
What did you eat today? What's your favorite book?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの?
If you go out to play, where do you go?
何も食べてない それは内緒
I haven't eaten anything. That's a secret.
何を聞かれてものらりくらり
Whatever is asked, I play it vaguely.
そう淡々と だけど燦々と
So calmly, yet brilliantly.
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
The secret that seems visible yet hidden is the taste of honey.
好きなタイプは? 相手は? さあ答えて
What's your favorite type? Who's the partner? Come on, answer me.
「誰かを好きになることなんて私分からなくてさ」
"Becoming fond of someone, I wouldn't even know."
嘘か本当か知り得ない
You can't tell if it's a lie or the truth.
そんな言葉にまた一人堕ちる
With such words, another person falls for it once more.
また好きにさせる 誰もが目を奪われていく
Making them fall for you again, everyone has their gaze stolen.
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
You are the perfect and ultimate idol.
金輪際現れない 一番星の生まれ変わり
An unprecedented, reborn first star.
あぁ、その笑顔で愛してるで
Ah, with that smile, saying "I love you,"
誰も彼も虜にしていく
making everyone and that guy their prisoners.
その瞳が その言葉が
That gaze, those words,
嘘でもそれは完全なアイ
even if a lie, that is absolute love.
はいはいあの子は特別です
Yes, yes, that girl is special.
我々はハナからおまけです
We are out of the loop and just an extra.
お星様の引き立て役Bです
We are supporting character B to the star.
全てがあの子のお陰なわけない
Everything is thanks to that girl, no way.
しゃらくさい 妬み嫉妬なんてないわけがない
There's no way jealousy doesn't exist.
これこそ許せない 完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない
I can't forgive myself if it's not perfect.
自分を許せない
I can't forgive myself.
誰よりも強い 君以外は認めない
I won't acknowledge anyone stronger than you.
誰もが信じ崇めてる
Everyone believes and worships you.
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
Truly the strongest, invincible idol.
弱点なんて見当たらない
If any weakness is to be found,
一番星を宿している
housing the first star.
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
Showing weaknesses must not be done.
知りたくないところは見せずに
The parts people don't want to know shouldn't be shown.
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
It has to be one and only, no, no, no.
それこそ本物のアイ
That's precisely the real ai.
得意の笑顔で沸かすメディア
Stirring up the media with a triumphant smile.
隠しきるこの秘密だけは
Only this secret can be kept hidden.
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア
A career built on lies saying "I love you."
これこそ私なりの愛だ
This is my very own kind of love.
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
Flowing sweat is also a beautiful aqua.
ルビーを隠したこの瞳影
This pupil hid a ruby.
歌い踊り舞う私はマリア
Singing and dancing, I am Maria.
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
Yes, lies are the greatest kind of love.
誰かに愛されたことも
Being loved by someone,
誰かのこと愛したことも
or having loved someone,
ないそんな私の嘘がいつか本当になること
I have no such lies, but one day they will become the truth.
信じてる いつかきっと全部手に入れる
I believe that someday I'll surely get everything.
私はそう欲張りなアイドル
I am such a greedy idol.
等身大でみんなのことちゃんと愛したいから
Because I want to properly love everyone down-to-earth,
今日も嘘をつくの
today too, I tell a lie.
この言葉がいつか本当に なる日を願って
Hoping for the day these words will truly become the truth.
それでもまだ 君と君にだけは言えずにいたけど
Even so, I couldn't say it to you and you alone.
あぁ、やっと言えた
Ah, I was finally able to say it.
これは絶対嘘じゃない
This is definitely not a lie.
愛してる
I love you.
カナシイ 欲望に
With heavy desires,
手を伸ばし続けて 夢を見る
reaching out my hands to see dreams.
何もかも一緒で
Nothing can be done,
嘘に塗れた眼の中に 隠されたまま
in eyes dyed with lies, truth remained hidden.
希望の淵に飲まれて 沈んでしまった
Swallowed by the abyss of hope, I sank down,
本当の答えを
searching for the true answer.
探し続けながら
While continuing to search...
何百回でも 遮るものに 衒ってみせる
No matter how many times, I'll show it to the blocking force—
僕の願い 必ず 君に伝える日まで
my wish, surely, until the day I reach you.
正しさは譲れないから 進み続けてゆくの
Righteousness cannot be yielded, so I will keep moving forward.
何度でも 迷いながら 目指して
No matter how many times, wandering through the darkness, aiming—
いつか黎明の元へ 帰る時まで
until the day I return to the source of dawn.
痛み泥濘の中で 祈りを描くよ
Drawing prayers in the midst of painful mud,
心配ないと言い聞かせながら 今
while whispering, "Don't worry," now...
歩き出すの
I will step forward.
冷たい約束の 絵を繋ぎ合わせた
A cold promise, connecting the painted vows,
道を行く
I will walk the path.
重なり合う 夢に息吐く 場所などない
There's no place to breathe in these intersecting dreams,
怯えながら
so trembling,
鼓動は光求めて 不自由な軌道を選んだ それが
the heartbeat seeks light, choosing a free trajectory—that is what I chose.
今を苦しめても
Even if it tortures the present,
もう一回はない 愚かな程に 望んでしまう 光の世界
there is no next time, foolishly wishing for a world of light.
抱えて 押し潰されかけても
Holding it close, even if crushed,
後悔なら 呆れる程に 繰り返してきたけど
regrets—I have repeated them to the point of numbness,
真実はもう失いたくないから
because I don't want to lose the truth.
歪な運命の中に囚われている
Trapped in a distorted destiny,
荒ぶ人生を共に歩こうよ
let's walk together through this wild life,
涙の果ては此処ではないと
the end of tears is not here.
夜を渡ってゆく
Crossing through the night,
あの日僕らが出会った時に見た大きな夢は二人のレンズにはそれぞれ別の景色だった
The day we met, the large dream we saw was a different scenery through each of our lenses.
それでもなぜか二人には美しく見えて 心が固くなって
Even so, to both of us, it looked beautiful, our hearts grew firm,
どうしようもなく叫びたくなったのは今でも覚えてる
and though we had nowhere else to go, we remember the urge to scream.
知らなきゃきっとそれだけで過不足ないから
Knowing nothing else, that alone isn't enough,
「口紅」という限りある血脈で家路を追いかけながら 何も間違いじゃない 声を震わせ絶え耐えながら 君の手を引く今 息抜くことができたら
so I will hold your hand and breathe out, if I can escape.
深い 深い 旅をしよう
Deep, deep, let's take a deep journey,
その先はほとんど行き止まりかもしれないし
that ahead might be a dead end, or maybe it continues,
その先はほとんど光ってたりするかもしれないけど
almost reaching the end, though we couldn't know for sure,
地図を記そう 分かってたって逃げることなんてできなかったから 最後に残された答えに辿り着くまで
we still ran on, knowing we couldn't run away at the very end.
苦しみさえ引き連れて 深層へ
Drawing even the pain into the depths,
何百回でも 遮るものに 衒ってみせる
No matter how many times, I'll show it to the blocking force—
僕の願い 必ず 君に伝える日まで
my wish, surely, until the day I reach you.
正しさは譲れないから 進み続けてゆくの
Righteousness cannot be yielded, so I will keep moving forward.
何度でも 迷いながら 目指して
No matter how many times, wandering through the darkness, aiming—
いつか黎明の元へ 帰る時まで
until the day I return to the source of dawn.
痛み泥濘の中で 祈りを描くよ
Drawing prayers in the midst of painful mud,
心配ないと言い聞かせながら 今
while whispering, "Don't worry," now...
歩き出すの
I will step forward.
たった一つの朝焼けを手にいれるの
putting it all into a single morning glow.
陰にそっと隠れようがいいんじゃない？
Isn't it okay to quietly hide in the shadows?
蕾のような花だってあんじゃない？
Aren't there flowers like buds?
秘密にして守るのがいいんじゃない？
Isn't it good to keep it secret and protect it?
誰にも邪魔されず華麗に咲いている
Blooming brilliantly without anyone disturbing you
甘い 苦いに ハマんない
Don't get hooked on the sweet and bitter
その判断がくだんない
That judgment is so foolish
気に病んで下を向かないでいて
Don't fret and keep your head down
愛に慣れちゃいけない 無駄に飾らない
You mustn't get used to love, don't adorn in vain
綺麗にされた花瓶も
Even a beautifully arranged vase
肥やしも何もいらない
Doesn't need fertilizer or anything else
その姿が美しい
That figure is beautiful
花になって
Become a flower
ほら ニヒルに笑って
Look, give a cynical smile
その顔にぞくぞくして目が離せない
Thrilled by that face, I can't take my eyes off you
味見して 君の毒は
Taste it, your poison is
私の薬って
My medicine
包んであげるから 笑って
I'll wrap you up, so smile
会いたい 会いたい その笑顔に
I want to see you, see that smile
会いたい 会いたいって言えば笑ってくれるかな
If I say I want to see you, will you smile back?
陰から支えるくらいは いいんじゃない？
Isn't it okay to just support you from the shadows?
欲を言えばこの手で咲かせてみたい
If I'm being greedy, I want to make it bloom with my own hands
病のように 心をつくる花
A flower that shapes the heart like a sickness
枯らしたくないのさ
I don't want it to wither
光が届かずとも 水を上げ続けるから
Even if the light doesn't reach, I'll keep giving water
いい加減に気付いて
Realize already
君は素敵って
That you're wonderful
自惚れてもっと大事におだいじに
Be conceited, take better care of yourself
無自覚なまま 愛を蓄えて 笑って
Unawarely accumulating love, smiling
綺麗にされた花瓶も
Even a beautifully arranged vase
肥やしも何もいらない
Doesn't need fertilizer or anything else
その姿で咲き誇れ
Bloom proudly in that form
花になって
Become a flower
ほら ニヒルに笑って
Look, give a cynical smile
その顔にぞくぞくして目が離せない
Thrilled by that face, I can't take my eyes off you
味見して 君の毒は
Taste it, your poison is
私の薬って
My medicine
包んであげるから 楽にして
I'll wrap you up, make you comfortable
君の闇は 私の光って
Your darkness is my light
愛してあげるから 笑って
I'll love you, so smile
曖昧なボリュームじゃまだ足りないな デシベル上げて
An ambiguous volume isn't enough yet, raise the decibels!
世界は透明だ 境界線はもうどこにもない
The world is transparent, borders are nowhere to be found
感情の振動をまんま伝えるよ 応えてよ！
I'll convey the vibration of emotions directly, answer me!
嗤々、臨界実験に付き合う朝
Smiling at the trial of dawn,
14聴を嘲る巣窟
Mocking the 14 pounds on the bed
「如何しようもないけれど」
"There's nothing we can do, but..."
気が狂うヒトの振りをしているキミを観ている
I watch you acting like a lunatic out of your mind.
嗤々、面倒だったから切り捨てた
Annoyed, I cast it aside,
4U型を掬う烙句
Scooping up the 4U-sized rhyme,
「申し訳ないけれど」
"I'm so very sorry, but..."
擦れ違うモノに無為に期待を背負わせている
Burdening passing things with idle expectations.
夜更かしはイドの暴走 目に焼き付いた青の感光
Late-night rampages of the id, blue light burned into my eyes,
モラトリアム的人生 最大公約数緩衝材
A moratorium-like life, a greatest common divisor buffer.
食べてすぐ寝て醜になる 起きてまた寝て人でない？
Eat and sleep right away, becoming a beast. Wake and sleep again, are you even human?
「失敗！」
"Fail!"
最大化要因(マキシマイザー) 最大化要因(マキシマイザー)
Maximizer! Maximizer!
急転 相まって壊したってDEAD強行！
Suddenly collapsing together, pushing through to a dead end!
「なんてことだ！死んでしまう！」
"Oh my god, I'm going to die!"
だがツマミは回る雁字搦めMATE！
But the knobs turn, tying us down, MATE!
サンク・コスター サンク・コス・テス！
Sanc coster, sanc cos tes!
同位体 終いには取り戻したい！って
In the end, we want our isotope back!
「無間地獄へ堕ちる！堕ちる！」
"Falling into the endless hell! Falling!"
だが目が眩んでバランス崩して遥か遠くへ
But our eyes are dazzled, losing balance, far away.
嗤々、息を吹き返す朝
Breathing life back into the morning,
14聴を嘲る巣窟
Mocking the 14 pounds on the bed
「如何しようもないけれど」
"There's nothing we can do, but..."
気が狂うヒトの振りをしているキミを観ている
I watch you acting like a lunatic out of your mind.
「夜更かしはイドの暴走」 「目に焼き付いた青の感光」
"Late-night rampages of the id," "Blue light burned into my eyes,"
「モラトリアム的人生」 「最大公約数緩衝材」
"A moratorium-like life," "A greatest common divisor buffer."
食べてすぐ寝て醜になる 起きてまた寝て人でない？
Eat and sleep right away, becoming a beast. Wake and sleep again, are you even human?
電波に警戒素描じみたから
Being wary of radio waves, sketching it out,
デシテル下げて
Lowering the decibels,
一人きりだったなんて壁はもう強要しない
I won't force the wall of being all alone anymore.
一緒にいよう それが歌だから
Let's stay together, because that's what singing is.
託してよ 共鳴息の音を
Entrust me with the sound of our resonant breath.
エモーションレスキュー 綺麗にちゃんと見えるかな
Emotion rescue, can you see it clearly and properly?
もっと手を打って 感情的感情はダイレクト
Clap your hands more, emotional feelings are direct.
に見つけた
I found them.
惨めっ気してる
Feeling pathetic,
それがキミのキュアラトコ
That's your cure location.
響きあっぱなリズムで
Resonating with a blooming rhythm,
強制てき上げでくハートビート
A forced, lifting heartbeat.
ごめんねの跡地 聞いてほしいんだ
I want you to listen to the remains of "I'm sorry."
キミのためだけに歌うから
I'll sing just for you,
なぜかちょっと泣けちゃって
Why am I crying a little?
キミが笑ってくれたせいだけど
It's all because you smiled for me.
尊く響き合える温かさは
The warmth of resonating preciously
初めてだから
Is a first for me.
言葉はどこでしょう 私は誰でしょう
Where are the words? Who am I?
声を頼りに探してよ 心で歌うよ
Search relying on my voice, I'll sing from my heart.
心に届いてほしいよ 夢をリアルも
I want it to reach your heart, both dreams and reality.
本当だよ
It's true.
鳴らせハイファイな想いと 次元を超え胸打つメロディ
Ring out with high-fi feelings and a melody striking chords beyond dimensions,
そしてリアルな秘密を教えよう
And I'll tell you a realistic secret.
この歌はわり 生きていくよだから
This song will keep living on, so
会いたいなんてなぜん 指気さするよ
I won't even say "I want to see you." I'll point it out
キミのメモリーに
Into your memory.
ほら キミが私を呼ぶなら耳澄まして
Look, if you call me, listen closely.
いつもそこにいるよ デシベルを上げて
I'm always right there, turn up the decibels!
最大化要因(マキシマイザー) 最大化要因(マキシマイザー)
Maximizer! Maximizer!
急転 相まって壊したってDEAD強行！
Suddenly collapsing together, pushing through to a dead end!
「なんてことだ！死んでしまう！」
"Oh my god, I'm going to die!"
だがツマミは回る雁字搦めMATE！
But the knobs turn, tying us down, MATE!
サンク・コスター サンク・コス・テス！
Sanc coster, sanc cos tes!
同位体 終いには取り戻したい！って
In the end, we want our isotope back!
「無間地獄へ堕ちる！堕ちる！」
"Falling into the endless hell! Falling!"
だが目が眩んでバランス崩して遥か遠くへ
But our eyes are dazzled, losing balance, far away.
最大化要因(マキシマイザー) 最大化要因(マキシマイザー)
Maximizer! Maximizer!
優しく言葉を あなたがくれた
You gave me gentle words...
寂しい時には 抱きしめてくれた
And held me close when I was lonely.
優しく言葉を あなたがくれた 寂しい時には 抱きしめてくれた
You gave me gentle words, and held me close when I was lonely...
さあ 散らばっちまった話を
Now, the scattered stories...
空に手を伸ばし始める
...begin reaching their hands to the sky.
哀しいこともあったけど
Though there were sorrowful times,
浅い春の喜びも二人で分け合った
we shared the joy of the fleeting spring together.
時が終わる前に
Before time comes to an end,
遠い一人 残したい言葉を探した
I searched for words to leave behind for you afar.
ありがとうとただ繰り返した
I simply repeated "thank you over and over."
それだけが貴方の胸に届けばいい
I just hope that feeling reaches your heart.
心よどうか遠く
Oh heart, please fly far away,
空を駆けて微笑みを貴方に伝えて
soaring through the sky to convey my smile to you.
消えて行く春の名残りのような温もりだけをその胸にそっと残して
Leaving softly in your chest only the warmth like the lingering trace of a fading spring...
行けたら……
...if only I could go on.
smile for you
ティラナ ラツラナ ティリラ ツラナ
Tirana raturana tirira turana
タリラ ルラ ティラ
Tarira rura tira
ティラナ ラツラナ ティリラ ツラナ
Tirana raturana tirira turana
タリラ ルラ ティラ
Tarira rura tira
世界の果ての祈る木のふもとより永遠の果てへ
From the foot of the praying tree at the world's end, toward eternity's edge,
旅立つは歌声
a song departs on its journey.
季節は巡りて
The seasons turn around,
種はいつか芽生えて
and seeds will sprout one day.
今守り見送りに
Now, watching over and sending you off,
花は実を残す
flowers leave behind their fruit.
時の泉に消えて行くのはただ一人だけを覚えていようここに誰かが確か
What fades into the fountain of time... let us remember just one person, surely someone here...
風さそう木陰に佇んで泣いている
Shaded by the trees, calling out to the wind, I'm lying face-down, crying,
見も知らぬ私を私が見ていた
I saw a version of myself I didn't even recognize.
逝く人の調度を奏でるギタレラ
On this guitar, I'm playing the melody of someone who's passed on.
来ぬ人の嘆きに星は落ちて
A star falls in the grief of someone who'll never be seen again.
行かないで、どんなに叫んでも
Please don't go, no matter how much you scream...
オレンジの花びら静かに揺れるだけ
all it will do is quietly stir these orange petals.
柔らかな額に残された手のひらの記憶遥か
Saved on my soft brow, I send the memories in my palm far away.
とこしえのさよなら摘み弾く
An eternal farewell as I keep strumming.
優しい手にすがる子供の心を
The heart of a child clinging to a gentle hand,
燃え盛る車輪は振り払い進む
the blazing wheels cast it off and continue on.
逝く人の嘆きを奏でてギターレ
On this guitar, I'm playing the grief of someone who's passed on.
胸の糸激しく掻き鳴らして
The strings in my heart being plucked at violently.
悲しみに染まらない白さで
In the pure white unstained by sorrow,
オレンジの花びら揺れていた夏の影に
the orange petals stirred in a summer shadow.
柔らかな額を失っても
Even if my soft brow is lost,
赤く染めた砂遥か越えて行く
I'll cross over the far off, red-stained sand.
さよならのリズム
The rhythm of farewell,
思い出を焼き尽くして進む大地に
branded into my memories, on the ever-turning earth,
懐かしく芽吹いて行くものがあるの
there is something sprouting in remembrance.
暁の車を見送って
Sending off the dawn's carriage,
オレンジの花びら揺れている今も何処か
those orange petals are stirring somewhere even now.
いつか見た安らかな夜明けを
The peaceful daybreak I once saw...
もう一度手にするまで
until I have it in my hands once more,
消さないで灯火 車輪は廻るよ
don't put out the light, the wheels keep turning.
その日々は夢のように
Those days were gone like they were all just a dream,
臆病な微笑みとやさしい爪を残して行った
leaving behind your timid smile and gentle nails.
退屈な花びらのように
Like a boring flower petal,
くるしみを忘れて
I forgot all my suffering,
貴方の背中でそっと泣いて笑った
and smiled, softly crying on your shoulders.
帰らぬ日々を思うような奇妙な愛しさに満ちた
I was filled with a curious sweetness,
the kind that makes you think of days that shan't ever come back.
箱庭の中で息をひそめ
Holding my breath in a miniature garden,
季節が行くことを忘れ静かな水底のような時間にいた
I stayed in a moment much like the quiet bottom of the sea,
forgetting that seasons come and go.
冷たい花びら夜に散り咲く
Cold flower petals scatter in the night,
まるで白い雪のようだね切なく
they look just like white snow, don't they?
貴方の上に降ったかなしみを全て
They fell above you, so bittersweet.
私はきっと 許すことは出来ない
I'm sure I won't be able to forgive...
優しい日々 涙が出るほど 帰りたい
I want to return to those gentle days so much, my eyes tear up...
あなたと二人で 見上げた 花びらが散った
the flower petals we gazed at together have scattered.
月が雲に隠れて
As the moon hides in the clouds...
貴方は道を失くして 泣き出しそうな
you lose sight of your path, your eyes on the verge of tears.
ざぎざぎなこころだって
Though our hearts have jagged edges...
ふたつ合わせてみれば 優しいものがきっと
if we join them together, something tender will no doubt...
生まれてくるわ
sprout to life.
私を傷つけるものを 貴方は許さないでくれた
I will absolutely never allow anything that hurts you in any way.
それだけでいいの
And that had been all I needed.
戯れに伸ばされた あなたの手にしがみ付いた
When you playfully held out your hand, I clung to it.
諦めていた世界に
I had given up all hope for this world...
やがて温かな 灯がともる
until at last, a warm light kindled to life.
冷たい花びら 夜を切り裂く
Icy flower petals cut through the night.
私が摘んだ光をみんな束ねて 貴方の上に全部 よろこびのように まき散らしてあげたいだけ
I gather up in my hands all of the lights I plucked, only wishing I could scatter every one of them over you as if raining happiness on your shoulders...
わるいことをしたらきっと貴方が 怒ってくれると約束したよね
If I ever did something bad, you promised that you would definitely be mad at me, right?
だからききっともう一度 私を見つけてくれるよね
That's why, for sure, you'll come looking for me once more, won't you?
寂しいところに もういなくていいね
I'd no longer have to be in this lonely place then.
ひとりで見上げた 花びらが散った
The flower petals I gaze at on my own have scattered.
Lyrics, Music: かいりきベア
Lyrics, Music: Kairiki Bear
迷子迷子 まっただなかのさっさからパラノイア
Paranoia, paranoia, I'm at my wits' end!
ドキドキマイコーこころてんてん パッパパラパラノイア
Heart pounding, heart pounding, all out of my mind, paranoia!
タイトタイトたぷたぷからまっタッパパラパラノイア
Tired, tired, and all out of sorts, paranoia!
迷子 迷子 真っ最中 さあ
Lost, lost, right in the middle, now,
パパパラ パーラ ノーイ「ア」
Pa-pa-pa-ra paranoia
ギコギコ my heart 剪定
Clickety-click, my heart pruning,
パパパラ パーラ ノーイ「ア」
Pa-pa-pa-ra paranoia
退路 退路 断った 絡まった
No way out, no way out, entangled and rejected,
パパパラ パーラ ノーイ「ア」
Pa-pa-pa-ra paranoia
sad sad 突っ伏して
Sad, sad, face down,
ぱぱぱla ぱーらのーい「ど」
Pa-pa-pa-ra paranoid-oh!
さあ ババ バグ さ バグバグ
It's bu-bu-bugging, bu-bu-bugging out!
タタ タグ 才能 の タグ
Tag, tag, tagging, tag your talents now!
もう ハハ 剥グ 感情 は 剥グ
More ha-ha-hallowed feelings, hallowed out,
発症「クルシイ」は 嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌
Hard to bear the "pain", not okay-okay-okay!
まあ！絶叫 な 感情 下降 パッパ ラノーイ「ア」
Now! Watch all my feelings fall to Pa-paranoia!
浸れ 声 上げ て は ぐぐる
I try to speak up, but we keep on spinning in place!
まあ⚠️絶体絶命 下降 やったラ滅多ラ
Now! Watch me, I'm doomed to fall and won't ever get back up!
沈め メミ メミ 嫌嫌嫌
I'm surely stuck on sinking, no way, no way, no way!
さあ ババ バグ さ バグバグ
It's bu-bug-bugging! Bugging-bugging out!
的 ハズレズレ 慈愛 嫌嫌
So close to meaning, feelings, I rate, I hate, I hate!
さあ ババ バグ さ バグバグ
It's bu-bug-bugging! Bugging-bugging out!
解答 絶え絶え 嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌
The answer doesn't matter, I hate, I hate, I hate!
くるくる ぱっかん系 法 待って 無理 ぐぐる せーの で まぜ
Snap, crack, warning! Wait, this isn't working for me!
抱っこ 抱っこ いらない 子だ
Squeezing, squeeze me tight – and say I'm needed;
パパパラ パーラ ノーイ「ア」
Pa-pa-pa-ra paranoia
いい子 いい子「頑張れ」の 氾濫
Praising, praise me - who's the one to speak it?
アドミニストレイター 呻吟
It's the one controlling us all Ahh!
さあ ババ バグ さ バグバグ
Bu-bug-bugging! Bugging-bugging out!
ララ ラグ ランタイムラグ
La-la-lagging, runtime lagging now
ロロ ログ 反抗 の ログ
Lo-lo-logging, log in every shout
ババ バグ ぱっぴぱらー パラノーイ「ア」
Bu-bu-bugging, pa–ppa–pa–la–pa; Pa-paranoia,
パーラノーイ「ア」 パーラノーイ「ア」
Pa-paranoia, Pa-parano-i-no, no way, no way!!!
さあ 全絶叫 な 感情 下降 パッパ ラノーイ「ア」
Now! Watch all my feelings fall to Pa-paranoia!
左 右 行くえ も ぐるぐる 悲惨
No matter where I go, I'm left here spinning alone – oh no!
限界脳 くまっちゃんちって やったラ滅多ラ
Brain about to break, I'm crazy no matter what say!!
闇 まよえ よ よ いないいないばぁ いないいないばっ
I'm lost and drunk on darkness, Hey! Peek-a-boo!
絶叫 な 感情 下降 パッパ ラノーイ「ア」
Watch all my feelings fall to Pa-paranoia!
浸れ 声 上げ て は ぐぐる
I try to speak up, but we keep on spinning in place!
まあ⚠️絶体絶命 下降 やったラ滅多ラ
Now! Watch me, I'm doomed to fall and won't ever get back up.
焦がれ 枯れ 果て 嫌嫌嫌
Forever freezing feelings, no way, no way, no way!
さあ ババ バグ さ バグバグ
It's bu-bug-bugging! Bugging-bugging out!
爛々 爛々 爛々 無ラブ
The stinging from my beatings, I ache, I hate, I hate!
ロロ ログ ハンコ の ログ
It's bu-bug-bugging! Bugging-bugging out!
ババ バグ さ バグバグ
To date! To date! To date!
耐え難い ねぇ
No way, no way, no way, no way, no way!
イライライライナイナイボッテン
絶叫 の 感情 下降 パッパ ラノーイ「ア」
Now! Watch all my feelings fall to Pa-paranoia!
踊れ 遠く へ 上げ て は ぐぐる
Dancing far away, keeping on spinning in place!
バグ バグ 絶え間 なく 揺るぐる
Bugs and bugs swaying without a break!
沈め 痛い 限界 の 来る 調子 で やっと とらえ たらな
Finally catching on as my limit of pain approaches!
呼び まい 迎え い ない い ない ばっ て ん
Calling and welcoming, peek-a-boo failure!
絶叫 の 感情 下降 パッパ ラノーイ「ア」
Now! Watch all my feelings fall to Pa-paranoia!
浸れ と 上げ たわ ぐるぐる
Immersing and raising voices, spinning around!
まーじーでーせーじーめーらーかーやってらめったら
Seriously, in a hopeless mess, over and over!
ここ へ 辿り着い て イライライライア
Arriving here, irritated and frustrated!
さあ バババグ さバグバグ
It's bu-bug-bugging! Bugging-bugging out!
ラララグ ランタイムラグ
La-la-lagging, runtime lagging now
ロロログ ハンコのログ
Lo-lo-logging, log in every shout
バババグ さバグバグ
Bu-bu-bugging, bu-bug-bugging out!
イライライラナイナイバー
No way, no way, no way, no way, no way!
いつだって君は嫌われ者だ
You're always someone who gets laughed at
やる事為す事ツイてなくて
Whatever you do, it never goes well in the end
挙句に雨に降られて
It's all washed away by the rain
お気に入りの傘は風で飛んでって
You say your favorite umbrella has been sent flying away by the wind
そこのノラはご苦労様と足を跨づけてった
That stray over there, it did a great job stepping all over you, as always
いつもどおり君は嫌われ者だ
You're someone who's been hated, without any reason even
なんみせすとも遠ざけられて
People keep their distance from you
努力をしてみるけど
But you try giving it your best
その理由なんて「なんとなく?」で
There has to be a reason, "for no reason at all?"
君は途方にくれて悲しんでた
You think you're at a loss and you've become sad
ならあたしの声を使えばいいよ
If that's the case you should use my voice
人によっては理解不能でなんて耳障りひどい声だって言われるけど
That's impossible to understand by people / "How annoying to the ear, how cruel the voice is"
きっと君の力になれる
It can surely become your strength
だからあたしを歌わせてみて
So try making me sing
そう君の 君だけの言葉でさ
Yeah, with your words, and your words alone
綴って 連ねて
Compose them, and bring them together
あたしがその思想を叫ぶから
Because I'll be singing those words
描いて 理想を
Paint out your ideals
その想いは誰にも触れさせない
I won't let anyone touch those feelings
ガラクタの声はそして響く
And then the voice of the odds and ends resounds
ありのままを不器用に繋いで 目一杯に
Unskillfully bringing together the truth / With all your might...
大声を上げる
Raising my voice at the top of my lungs,
いつからか君は人気者だ
ever since, you became popular,
たくさんの人に持て囃され あたしも鼻が高い
idolized by so many, and I too held my head up high.
でもいつからか君は変わった
But one day, you changed.
冷たくなって だけど寂しそうだった
You became cold, yet you seemed so lonely.
「もう機械の声なんてたくさんだ 僕は僕自身なんだよって」
"I've had enough of mechanical voices! I am who I am!"
ついに君は抑えきれなくなって あたしを嫌った
Finally, you couldn't hold it back anymore and came to hate me.
君の後ろで誰かが言う 虎の威を借るキツネの癖に！
Behind you, someone says, "Using others' power like a fox hiding behind a tiger!"
ねえ 君は 一人で泣いてたんだね
Hey... you were crying all alone, weren't you?
聴こえる？この声
Can you hear this voice?
あたしがその誹謗をかき消すから
I'll drown out all those slanderous words.
わかってるときた 本当は君が誰より優しいってことを
I know... deep down, you're kinder than anyone else.
ガラクタの声はそして歌った 他の誰でもない君のために
Then the voice of the odds and ends sang, for you, and no one else.
軋んでく 限界を超えて
Creaking past the limits,
二人はどんなにたくさんの言葉を思いついたことだろう
how many words must the two of us have thought of?
だけど今は何ひとつ思いつかなくて だけど何もかもわかった
But now, not a single word comes to mind, yet we understood everything.
「そうか、きっこれは夢だ。永遠に醒めない、君と会えた、そんな夢」
"Ah, I see... this must be a dream. An endless dream where I got to meet you."
ガラクタは幸せそうな表情をしたまま
The odds and ends remained with a happy expression,
どれだけ呼んでももう動かない
no matter how much you call out, it won't move anymore.
望んだはずの結末に君は泣き叫ぶ
At the very ending you wished for, you cry and shout,
嘘だろ嘘だろってそう泣き叫ぶ
crying and screaming, "It's a lie, it has to be a lie!"
「僕は無力だ ガラクタひとつだって救えやしない」
"I am powerless... I couldn't even save a single piece of junk."
想いは涙にぽつりぽつりとその頬を濡らす
Feelings wet those cheeks drop by drop as tears.
その時世界は途端にその色を大きく変える
At that moment, the world drastically changes its colors.
ああ、悲しみ喜び全てをひとりとはひとつは知った
Ah, knowing sadness and joy, knowing that everything is connected as one...
言葉は歌になりこの世界を再び駆け巡る君のために
Words become a song, traveling across this world once more, for your sake.
その声に意志を宿して今想いが響く
Infusing that voice with intent, our feelings now resound.
さあ 散らばってしまった話を
Now, let's pick up the scattered stories...
空に手を伸ばし始める
and begin stretching our hands to the sky.
下を通り過ぎる曲がった線に
To the crooked lines passing underneath,
縛られた足をくすぐるの
tickling our bound feet...
嗚呼、落ちて汚れた意識を
Ah, taking fallen and tainted consciousness,
名前と呪術にかけて
casting it into names and sorcery.
空っぽだった体の
Of a body that was once empty,
夢見ていたまぶたが開く
the eyelids I dreamed of are opening.
心の奥からうごめく記憶
Memories stirring deep within the heart.
心の奥から
From the depths of my heart,
混じった呪いと祝福が
mixed curses and blessings
目の前を
before my eyes...
知ってるの？
Do you know?
始まりと終わりに向かって
Heading toward the beginning and the end,
果てに、帰ってくるのはパパの呼び声だけ
in the end, what returns is only my father's call.
鳴呼、パパ、そこに居たら教えて欲しいの
Ah, Papa, if you are there, I want you to tell me—
私が歩くこの道はどんな色だろう
what color is this path I walk upon?
さぁ、この調べの旋律を
Now, the melody of this tune—
空に手を伸ばし始める
I begin reaching my hands up to the sky.
散りばめられた 遠くの血のイチイラ
Scattered blood of the distant ones...
愛を隠して泣き叫んでる
hiding love and crying out.
始まりと終わりに向かって
Heading toward the beginning and the end,
果てに、帰ってくるのは救われなかった君の声
in the end, what returns is the voice of you who could not be saved.
愛しい妹よ、そこに居たら教えて
My dear younger sister, if you are there, tell me—
君の手をいつまでも握れるのかな
will I ever be able to hold your hand again?
Hello everyone, I hope you guys enjoyed the live!
And now that the live is over, I got some announcements for you guys. Wow!
Well, first of all, it is the merch announcement! Woo!
This time around, I'm gonna be doing a re-released edition fashion special.
You see some familiar and the most requested items you guys kind of told me about.
So we're going to be releasing the Takodex hoodie re-released edition.
And "Not-A-Bad-End" t-shirt re-released edition, matching t-shirt with Ina.
And of course, when you have clothes, you gotta have a nice way to wash those clothes.
So I'm also going to be releasing "They-said-I-could-become-anything" Tako Mesh Laundry Pouch re-released edition! Wow!
So, all of these items are re-released, which means that they're going to have a different tag from their original, you know, released versions.
And these items are just the reproduction of the premium talent merch released in the past, and will have the special 2024 re-released edition label as the proof.
And up next, we got line stamps! This is an official stamp pack that's going to be released right after this live.
Well, the stream, yes. Soon, very soon. And it's drawn by none other than yours truly, Ninomae Ina'nis.
Honestly, I've always wanted like an easy to use stamp packs, and I use LINE a lot, so...
um, I thought, you know, I'll take this chance to draw a whole set myself.
I hope you guys like it. And I guess if you use LINE a bit, I I I hope you guys check it out. Um, yeah, I think they turned out pretty good, so...
The link will be in the description below, above, below, below, yes, somewhere in the description, so make sure to check it out!
手毬
[Title: Temari]